Guide to the Morris and Dorothy Margolin film collection, 1947-1982 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Reel 12: Aruba, 1962
  people waiting in airport
  debarking from airplane
  tourists at hotel pool
  sailboat
  churches
  outdoor produce stand
  women walking with baskets on heads
  water skiing
  native barge
  man standing and paddling in a small "canoe" filled with green bananas
  people walking a dog down a side walk
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (325 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: est. 9:01) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: est. 9:01) (Box TBD)
- Reel 13: Italy (Naples, Taormina), Israel, Cristoforo Colombo (ship), 1964
  life preserver: C. Colombo Genova
  travelers on deck of ocean liner Cristoforo Colombo
  men in dinghy trying to sell goods to people on ocean liner, goods travel up a rope port
  Pompeii
  ruins, museum
  Napoli
  streets scenes
  mosque
  children
  piazza
  girl in first communion dress
  cafes
  view of mountain
  hilltop park
  Israel:
  border guards
  people working in fields
  sign: "Yad Mordekhai"
  hotel
  archeological sites
  people in orchard
  ruins of Roman baths with curative waters
  synagogue
  sign: "Eastern Bridge"
  Cesarea
  playing games with people at a settlement
  construction sites and new buildings
  palace, including grounds
  mosques
  aerial view of harbor city
  sign: "General Exhibition of Safad Artists"
  Jerusalem:
  sign: "King David's Tomb"
  sign: "Chamber of Destruction"
  Mount of Olives
  Mount Zion
  roads
  university campus
  couple walking arm and arm on a curved sidewalk
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (1150 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 43:34) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 43:34) (Box 1)
- Reel 14: Yugoslavia, Greece, 1964
  title card: "Vagabonds in Foreign Lands"
  title card: Produced by Margolin
  title card: Directed by Margolin
  title card: Costumes by Margolin
  title card: Casting by Margolin
  title card: Music Sound by Margolin
  title card: Financed by Margolin
  title card: Photography by Margolin
  Cast / Morris - Fuehrer / Kal - A Runner / Eleanor - Prime Minister / Dorothy - Shlepalong
  boats in harbor in Greece
  Dorothy on boat with Kal?
  boat sets sail, views of the water and shore
  Dorothy and Eleanor? on deck
  Dorothy poses with view of city behind her
  views of towns and harbors from the boat
  street scenes, including enormous pelican
  small boat on the water
  man rides donkey up and out of tunnel
  boat docks
  buildings on the mountainside
  man rolls barrel along street
  harbor scenes
  countryside, including mountains
  Kal?, Dorothy, Eleanor? exit museum? one at a time
  Acropolis
  Dorothy poses at the Acropolis, then at Parthenon
  Morris poses at the Parthenon
  Dorothy walks into the frame, pans to Greek flag in distance
  close-up of Parthenon columns
  aerial views of Athens
  close-up of Greek flag
  views of the Parthenon
  amphitheatre
  beach and seaside buildings
  scenes from street market
  close-ups on produce
  Dorothy? walks down narrow street
  man gets his hair cut
  street scenes, including street sweeper
  Dorothy walks down narrow street
  Dorothy talks to man on the street
  women balancing baskets on their head
  school group? walks along street
  people at fountain
  pigeons fly around square
  women in traditional clothing
  Dorothy stands on steps, pans to street and hillside
  woman in blue dress walks down steps
  man in uniform walks down steps
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (400 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 11:47) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 11:47) (Box 1)
- Reel 15: Japan, 1965
  exterior of store camera at a 90 degree angle
  city street scenes of native people dressed in Western clothing and traditional Japanese clothing
  outdoor sculptures
  Rodin sculptures
  river
  kites
  sign: "Uyeno Seiyoken"
  office buildings
  sign: "Buddhist Temple: Kotoku-In Monastery Kamakura"
  school group at the temple
  boats/junks on land
  pagodas
  view from train
  funicular up a mountain
  man boiling eggs in a hot spring
  tourist ferry boat
  boats in harbor
  train station
  women in kimonos
  street parade
  museum commemorating victims of Hiroshima
  hot springs
  formal procession
  pagoda
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (800 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 22:42) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 22:42) (Box 1)
- Reel 16: Bangkok, Hong Kong, 1965
  "Hong Kong Water Tours" flap flying from mast of boat
  Hong Kong
  wooden ferry boat
  view of skyline from the boat
  sign: "Kowloon Public Pier"
  harbor crowded with houseboats
  people fishing from small boat
  people walking
  modern hotel with beach and golf course
  Bangkok
  sign: "Tiger pagoda- exterior and detail"
  hotels
  apartment houses
  monkey
  outdoor café
  houseboats
  flooded rice patties
  sights of other boats, structures, houses and people as seen from a boat going down river
  people swimming and bathing in the river
  vendors selling merchandise from their small boats
  Buddhist temple, including interior, exterior, grounds
  Buddhist monks
  buildings and another boat on river viewed from a traveling boat
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (950 ft.) (Box 2)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 28:01) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 28:01) (Box 1)
- Reel 17: Hawaii, Pakistan, Turkey, Portugal, 1965
  palm trees
  Hawaii
  hula dance performance with guitar accompanists
  group of tourists learn to hula dance
  man climbing a palm tree
  sailboats at the edge of beach
  Pakistan? Turkey?
  street market
  vendors
  village huts outside of the city
  oxen
  outdoor laundry
  unidentified palace
  camel
  café on a beach
  trams
  exterior and interior and grounds of palace or museum
  sign: "Baghdad Kiosk"
  men washing feet
  temple or mosque?
  obelisks
  aerial view of coliseum, city, bay
  interior of airplane, flight attendants
  Portugal
  outdoor produce market
  fishermen repairing nets and boats
  exteriors of buildings
  town square
  village life
  women washing laundry
  sign: "Convento de Santa Cruz dos Capuchos"
  exteriors of Palacio Hotel
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (900 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 25:20) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 25:20) (Box 1)
- Reel 18: France (Paris, Deauville, the Riviera), 1967
  traffic circle in Paris, vehicles driving around an obelisk
  sign: "Place Vendome"
  scale models of ocean liners
  sign: "Avenue De L'Opera"
  L'Opera
  Gendarme
  cinema
  film posters
  streetcar
  construction workers
  advertisements
  sign: "Rue St. Honoré"
  sign: "Boulevard St. Germain"
  Place St. Genevieve
  Anti-Vietnam War and Anti-American posters
  Seine River
  Notre Dame
  people on the banks of the Seine
  Deauxville
  waterfront
  vehicles
  café
  horse and buggy
  sign: "Avenue General De Gaulle"
  New Golf Club in Deauville
  statue honoring the dead of World War II
  outdoor street market
  statue of Joan of Arc
  sign: "Rue de Rivoli"
  Champs-élysées
  Arc De Triomphe
  George V Hotel
  Folies Bergère poster
  sign: "Champs Elysees"
  Maria Callas poster
  Christian Dior boutique
  Eiffel Tower
  sign: "Rue De Seine"
  tourist tour boat
  University of Paris
  sign: "Quai des Tuileries"
  sign: "Rue de la Paix"
  sign: "Boulevard des Capucines
  sign: "Rue Danou"
  French Riviera
  palm trees and Paramount film posters
  Cannes?
  film posters and advertisements
  outdoor beachfront café
  people on the beach
  airport
  people boarding an airplane
  boats in a harbor
  fisherman unloading nets
  photo shoot of a model in a bikini
  Chartres cathedral?
  front of Chartres Cathedral
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (850 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 33:06) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 33:06) (Box 1)
- Reel 19: Morocco, Italy, 1967
  prow of the ocean liner Michelangelo
  people seeing off the ship from dock
  travelers on deck of ship
  ship captain piloting ship
  Port of Genoa
  Morocco
  donkeys/mules
  people filling up water at an outdoor faucet
  men praying
  women in burkahs
  acrobats performing on street
  interior of mosque
  cemetery
  castle or fortress
  directional signs: Beni Mellal, Kasba Tadla, El Kelaa and Marrakesh
  sheep and herder
  Marrakesh
  children walking home from school
  rug weavers at looms
  sign: "Cooperative Artisanale D'Azrou"
  city street scenes
  sign: "Arab Bank"
  sign: "Proprieté Jacque Majorelle"
  laundry
  sign: "Hotel La Mamounia"
  parade or march
  street performers
  snake charmer
  street dancers and musicians
  sign: "Casbah"
  Casbah garden
  Venice
  motorboat ride
  view of Venice from canal
  gondolas
  breakfast on balcony
  canals
  palaces
  bridges
  sign: "Hotel Bauer Grunwald"
  flags flying
  Doge's Palace
  artists painting at easels in piazza
  interior of restaurant
  pigeons
  children and nuns in a procession
  group of young people walking through a piazza
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (1200 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 43:14) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 43:13) (Box 1)
- Reel 20: USSR (Moscow, Kiev, Yalta, Sochi), 1958, 1964, 1967
  The original film was labeled 1967, but edge code on the 16mm reversal original indicates that sections of this film pre-date 1967; more details are available on the film's Print Condition Report. It is possible, though, that the Margolins took more than one to the Soviet Union in the 1950s and 1960s.
  onion-domed buildings shot from across river
  street scene, traffic
  State Historical Museum, Red Square, the Kremlin
  goose-stepping guards marching in front of Lenin's Mausoleum
  long line outside of Lenin's Mausoleum on Red Square
  Saint Basil's Cathedral
  children wearing uniforms, holding red flags on Red Square
  long line for Lenin's Mausoleum wraps around Red Square
  school children walking in line
  Tsar Bell
  group of school children in uniform
  Red Square
  building with large columns
  Moscow State University
  view of Moscow from Sparrow Hill, Moskva River
  sign: "Hotel Berlin" (also in Russian)
  Hotel Berlin and environs
  street scenes, including Dorothy
  banner in Russian
  park, food vendors
  entrance arch to the All-Russia Exhibition Center
  the All-Russia Exhibition Center, including sign in Russian
  close-up on statue on top of entrance arch
  scenes from the All-Russia Exhibition Center, including fountains, statues, architecture, red flags
  photographer takes picture of fellow travelers
  food vendors
  wide promenade with entrance arch in the distance
  ornate fountain
  food vendors and hungry school children
  more scenes from All-Russie Exhibition
  sign: arrow points left, in Russian
  Dorothy and friend? toward camera
  close-up of building, the Bolshoi Theatre?
  river scenes, including large ship, Neva River in St. Petersburg?
  Bronze Horseman statue of Peter the Great, St. Petersburg
  exterior of St. Isaac's Cathedral
  street scenes, including historic architecture
  construction workers spreading asphalt
  exterior shots of the Hermitage
  exterior of the Church of Our Savior on Spilled Blood, some scaffolding
  architecture, street scenes
  Neva River
  Battleship Aurora, open to tourists
  sailor walking away on sidewalk along the bank of the Neva River
  Dorothy Margolin with guard outside of Peterhof Palace
  Peterhof Palace gardens
  school group touring Peterhof Palace gardens, close-up on faces of young boys
  Dorothy poses with a group of schoolgirls
  statue
  kids play in fountain, sprinkler drenches garden
  Neva River?
  workers cultivate grass
  Catherine Palace
  older women sitting on bench outside of palace
  restoration work performed on Catherine Palace
  horse passes under archway
  apartment building?
  St. Petersburg Mosque, ornate exterior alcove
  gates to unidentified, passersby
  Smolny Cathedral?
  parking lot
  unidentified yellow building behind trees
  wide boulevard, possibly Nevsky Prospekt?
  tracking shot along bridge over canal, Church of Our Savior on Spilled Blood in background
  exterior of Kazan Cathedral
  exteriors of Grand Choral Synagogue
  woman pastes up street advertisements, street scene
  statue of Lenin on pillar, flowers below, in Kiev, Ukraine
  four uniformed men walk by on sidewalk, high angle shot from upstairs window
  woman painting wall
  women working on railroad construction
  street scene from inside car, framed by windshield
  long shot of statue, from across the street
  red building with explanatory sign outside
  sidewalk scene, open yellow door (sign in Cyrillic)
  sign: "Hashian"
  exteriors of St. Michael's Golden-Domed Monastery?
  intercut with people on nearby sidewalk, inc. Dorothy and friend
  open square, large group of people walking toward camera
  exteriors Kiev Pechersk Lavra?
  school children and others walk by
  scaffolding and restoration work
  landscape shots overlooking the Dnieper River, fade to black
  man walks over to food stand?
  sidewalk scenes, Kiev?
  street musicians
  sign in Cyrillic
  blue building, unknown
  two uniformed schoolgirls walk toward camera
  long shot of Mother Motherland statue? from other side of hill
  high angle shot of billboards
  memorial statue and plaque: Cyrillic
  workers digging in park
  scenes of Park of Glory (Park Slavi), including Fallen Heroes Alley, fade to black
  eternal flame at base of Obelisk of Glory, surrounded by flowers
  view from base of Obelisk of Glory
  street scenes as shot from the car, windshield and dashboard visible
  exteriors of utilitarian apartment buildings, new constructions
  memorial and surrounding greenery
  sign: "Intourist [sic]-- Hotel-Restaurant -- Oreanda"
  Hotel Oreanda, Yalta
  women crossing street, toward camera; includes Dorothy
  1917-1967 anniversary banner for the Red Revolution on Hotel Oreanda
  street food vendor
  red flag flies among street lights
  street scenes, inc. shot of Dorothy and Morris?
  Hotel Oreanda; Dorothy waits outside with friend
  Dorothy and friend walk toward Livadia Palace
  Livadia Palace architecture and grounds
  Livadia Palace gardens and view of the Black Sea, includes shot of women working in the garden
  Morris walks into frame and sits on bench
  views of hillside neighborhood and Black Sea
  Morris with Livadia Palace and Black Sea in the background
  landscape
  fade to black
  white statues, museum interiors
  white lion statue at Vorontsov Palace; Dorothy walks into shot
  people working on gardens at Vorontsov Palace
  Dorothy and friend? walk toward camera holding hands (multiple takes)
  small group pauses at top of steps, gardener walks up
  landscape shot of gardens and Black Sea, people sit on benches in foreground
  Vorontsov Palace walls
  sign related to 1917-1967 anniversary
  food vendor
  people gathering for group shot in courtyard
  unidentified building
  indoor/outdoor food and flower market; seems rural
  busts in park; fade to black
  children eating ice cream cones on bench, Soviet era posters in background
  ice cream vendor, children buy ice cream
  garden square with memorial tree and flowers; sign in Cyrillic
  hotel; very mod
  landscape view of rolling hilltops
  unknown rustic restaurant, park?; fade to black
  unknown building; sign in Cyrillic
  truck transporting logs drives by
  Soviet advertisement, perhaps propaganda; in Cyrillic
  statue in front of streetlight on road median
  mod building, maybe a bus stop or convenience store?
  farmland along river
  dance performance in a theater
  Dorothy stands by a fence with a view of town in the background
  Morris stands in same place with pipe in hand, waves goodbye
  - Reversal original, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (1200 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 35:54) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 35:54) (Box 1)
- Reel 21: USSR, 1967
  This film does not appear to have been made by Morris Margolin; rather, it is likely that it is a documentary film acquired by the Margolins on their trip to the Soviet Union.
  - Positive print, 16mm, so., co., reel 1 of 1, (1100 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 31:49) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 31:49) (Box 1)
- Reel 22: Capri - Ethiopia - Nairobi, Kenya - Cape Town - Johannesburg - Safari, October 1971
  flowers on windowsill, landscape from window
  sign: "Servizio Motoscafi per la Grotta Azzurra"
  street scenes, including Bar Grotta Azzurra
  boats at dock
  street scenes, including street vendor
  boats and buildings along shore
  close up on sign: "Servizio Motoscafi per la Grotta Azzurra / Andata e ritorno L. 300
  buildings near water, on cliff
  beach from a distance
  men on dock working with net
  woman fills bucket with water at spigot
  street scenes, including cafes and shops
  Dorothy sits near bottom of stairs
  ships on the water
  Dorothy and friend? walk with crowd toward camera
  high-angle shots of people in canoes, boats near La Grotta Azzurra
  people exit canoes, line for canoe rides
  Dorothy and friend? in canoe
  views of landscape
  exteriors of a villa?
  Dorothy under a covered walkway
  walkway flanked by trees
  sign: "San Michele di Axel Munthe"
  Dorothy walks out of doorway
  plaque about Axel Munthe (in Italian)
  two people tend to garden
  clock tower
  building: Hotel Quisiana
  scenes at the dock, includes sign: "Diretto Sorrento"
  Dorothy and friends wait with luggage
  views of harbor and boats, shot from boat
  garden or park? in Ethiopia
  crowd on hillside
  livestock
  street scenes, including Dorothy, people gathering? at roundabout
  two men shake hands
  well-dressed young people line-up
  plaque: in Amharic?
  plaque: "His Imperial Majesty Haile Selassie the First Emperor of Ethiopia In Order to Promote and Improve the Services of Posts and Telecommunications for the Benefit of His People Inaugurated These Buildings on This 2nd Day of November 1969 on the Thirty Ninth Year of His Reign"
  sign: "Minister of State"
  street scenes, construction
  exteriors of building, parking lot
  street scenes, crowd gathered
  Dorothy amongst the crowd
  crowd gathered around street performance
  sign: "Terefe Guta House Rent & Real Estate Broker"
  exteriors of buildings, street scenes
  close-up on painting, underexposed
  Ethiopian flag flaps in distance, behind trees
  scenes of impoverished area
  buildings, mountains off in the distance
  lion statue
  man in traditional clothing
  H.I.M. Menelik mausoleum
  exterior shots of unidentified building
  close-ups on stained glass with religious motifs
  building under construction?
  exteriors of unidentified buildings, gardens
  Dorothy walks toward the camera
  sign: "Haile Selassie I University"
  exteriors of buildings, presumably at the university
  Dorothy on the roadside, sign behind her reads: "You are now entering Kenya"
  sign: "Nairobi Hebrew Congregation Services"
  exteriors of synagogue
  sign: "University of Nairobi"
  exteriors of unidentified buildings
  Dorothy walks around sculpture, toward camera
  close-ups of sculptures
  plaque: "In grateful remembrance of Dr. R.K. Yajnik"
  building: University of Nairobi
  creek
  cityscape
  giraffes
  sign: "White Grass Ridge / Beware of Lions"
  zebras, other wildlife
  scenes from the savanna
  primates (baboons?), one sits on the hood of a car
  hippos in the water
  locals and tourists on a path
  antelope?
  sign: "Hyaena Dam / Narogomon Dam"
  ostrich
  lioness walks from behind van
  landscape shots
  warthogs
  gazelle?
  running ostrich
  giraffe
  city skyline, buildings
  sign: "Golden City Hotel"
  sign: "Jewish Guild War Memorial" (Johannesburg, South Africa?)
  building with scaffolding
  street scenes, exteriors of buildings
  Hotel Monte Carlo
  Barclays Bank
  men loading cargo
  Tollman Towers
  street scenes, including Foschini, Woolworths
  skyline of Johannesburg?
  Dorothy and friends in a neighborhood
  Johannesburg airport
  clouds, countryside, towns from plane
  plane lands in Cape Town?
  skyline
  teacher and schoolgirls walk by
  sign on truck: Katz & Co. / High Class Confectioners / Wedding Cakes & Pastries our Specialty
  bus, street scenes
  traffic cop directs traffic outside of the Board of Executors
  sign: "Twenty Four Hours of Prayer for Racial Harmony in St. Georges Cathedral"
  Houses of Parliament in Cape Town
  statue of Victoria R.I.
  sign: "Government Ave"
  garden, men working near statue
  sign: "Art-Gallery / Museum"
  Table Mountain
  aerial view of Cape Town, including the harbor
  Jameson Memorial Hall
  Dorothy at University of Cape Town?
  young people on lawn, steps
  chauffeur leans against black car
  cars parked on street
  sign: "University of Cape Town"
  unidentified structure on hillside
  boat: Good Hope Castle
  industrial scenes of port
  billboard for Ackermans, "A family friendly store where you get... Value for your Money"
  people, boats in Cape Town harbor and port
  building: Port Offices - Hawekantore
  seagulls
  boat: H. Sawyer, Cape Town
  aerial views of city and surrounding area, including the ocean
  Dorothy and man look out at city
  plaque: "This cornerstone was placed in position in the House of God at sea point Cape Town by the right Hon. J.C. Smuts P.C., M.P., Minister of Justice"
  exteriors of buildings, close-up on door
  Castle of Good Hope
  sign: "Visitors to the Castle / William Fehr Collection Military Museum / Enquiries"
  school group walks past the camera
  aerial views of oceanfront and ocean, city and mountains
  sign: "Chapmans Peak"
  sign: "Cape of Good Hope Nature Reserve"
  scenery shot from moving car
  sign: "Cape Town 37"
  monkeys? peek in through vent on bus
  Dorothy poses with ocean in background
  sign: "Whites / Men & Women / Toilets"
  people climb hill toward unidentified building
  sign: "Toilets / Non Whites / Men & Women"
  sign: "Viewpoint"
  views of cliffs, ocean
  unidentified building on hilltop
  - Reversal original, Super 8mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, (600 ft.) (Box 3)
  - Preservation tape master, Digital Betacam, (TRT: 43:14) (Box TBD)
  - Preservation DVD master, (TRT: 43:14) (Box 1)
- Reel 23: TreeTops - Tanzania - Kenya - Safari Club / Safari - Ngorongoro Crater - Durban - Zulu Land, October 1971
  cartoon drawings of Dorothy and Morris with a huge lion between them
  entrance to Mount Kenya Safari & Game Ranch
  Morris stands next to sign: "Mount Kenya Safari Club"
  Morris in field
  Dorothy in garden
  views of sports club and garden area
  unidentified couple goofs around, bumps into Dorothy
  sign: "Danger / Wild Animals / Stay in Your vehicle / No Pedestrians / Speed Limit 15 Miles Per Hour"
  animals, some in cages others on safari: warthogs, antelopes, giraffes, leopards, monkeys, gorillas, dik-diks, zebras
  antelope? approaches car, sticks head in the window
  exterior of Outspan Hotel
  Dorothy sits at table
  people gather in outdoor café
  Dorothy and group on tour, at least one man with a rifle
  landscapes, some with animals
  Dorothy looks out over landscape from bridge
  Dorothy and group on lookout bridge
  close-ups on birds
  Dorothy and group eat snacks from table
  Dorothy with group of locals selling beaded necklaces
  close-ups on locals
  rural village
  small child walks toward camera, herding animals?
  landscapes, some with animals (including rhinos)
  sand storm
  group of identical tent-like structures
  Dorothy walks out of tent #15